<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Introduction on A Loafer's Guide to the U.C. Berkeley Campus</title><link>http://loafersguide.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Introduction on A Loafer's Guide to the U.C. Berkeley Campus</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://loafersguide.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>http://loafersguide.github.io/guide/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://loafersguide.github.io/guide/introduction/</guid><description>I started this book while attending graduate school at Berkeley in 1987, and completed the manuscript (to the extent that it is completed) in 1994, at which time I was living in the Midwest and was unable to show it to anyone who might have been interested. As I state in the following Prolog, a book like this is dated before it&amp;rsquo;s begun &amp;mdash; in the six years since I finished it several buildings have been demolished and several more of varying quality and prominence have been added to the campus.</description></item><item><title>Prolog</title><link>http://loafersguide.github.io/guide/prolog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://loafersguide.github.io/guide/prolog/</guid><description>Founder’s Rock sits in an isolated spot in the far northeastern corner of the main campus, surrounded but not shaded by native trees. It is a surprisingly comfortable seat and would be an excellent place to read, write or think if not for the proximity of the intersection of Hearst and Gayley. On its flat northern face is a plaque which reads
Founder’s Rock
April 16, 1860
Inscribed May 9, 1896.</description></item><item><title>History &amp; Development</title><link>http://loafersguide.github.io/guide/history-and-development/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://loafersguide.github.io/guide/history-and-development/</guid><description>This University is nearly a century and a half old — not long by European or even American standards, but mature for the West Coast. Although the Society of Jesus founded Santa Clara College, now the University of Santa Clara, in 1851, it was not chartered until 1855, after the College of California, now the University of California, was incorporated. Stanford, founded in 1891, is a baby by comparison. This is why it is known as the “junior university”; it still believes that someday it will catch up.</description></item><item><title>The Existing Campus</title><link>http://loafersguide.github.io/guide/existing-campus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://loafersguide.github.io/guide/existing-campus/</guid><description>Concordance of Building Names (or, Which Moses was Moses Hall Named After?) Academic buildings Anthony (1957) Earle C., Los Angeles-based dealer of Packard cars, and the world’s prominent Packard dealer. He owned a radio station and several showrooms, introduced neon signage to the US, was the first to put a gasoline pump at the curb for quickstop fuel purchases, and was instrumental in encouraging the building of the Golden Gate Bridge to promote driving and car sales (thanks to John Hempel and to George Hamlin, Vice President and International Liaison of the Packard Club, for educating me on this subject).</description></item><item><title>Resources</title><link>http://loafersguide.github.io/guide/resources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://loafersguide.github.io/guide/resources/</guid><description>Libraries Tired of suffocating in the mess at Moffitt? Keep running into the same old crowd at Eshleman? Maybe a trip to one of Berkeley’s 21 branch libraries and innumerable department, building, graduate school and other libraries might liven up your study time. Our Library Reviewer has checked out a few of them:
Biosciences (40 Gianini) Underground, dark and spooky, with gray metal shelves. A good place to go if you are having trouble getting access to library computer terminals.</description></item><item><title>Epilog</title><link>http://loafersguide.github.io/guide/epilog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://loafersguide.github.io/guide/epilog/</guid><description>A Trip Down the Wurster Stairwell Most Environmental Design students, and some others, understand about Wurster Hall. Its design and construction were greeted with considerable verbiage on the part of the committee that created it:
The solution [to the design problem] lay not in adherence to any single ideology or dogma, but rather in finding a reasonable path among a great array of conflicting and competing requirements… giving the greatest importance to conflicting requirements and… finding a way so that the status of each requirement and its conflicts was preserved… We sought not to resolve conflict but to preserve it.</description></item><item><title>Bibliography</title><link>http://loafersguide.github.io/guide/bibliography/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://loafersguide.github.io/guide/bibliography/</guid><description>Most of what is in this book I have seen, heard, experienced or read about in the Dail Cal. Aside from the usual guides to and histories of the city and campus, I recommend the following to those interested in the buildings, personalities and traditions of the University.
Campus Planning Study Group. Campus Historic Resources Survey. Berkeley, 1978. Everything you could possibly want to know about every piece of architecture on campus.</description></item></channel></rss>